# Ang Wei Jie

# **Data Analyst**

in linkedin.com/in/angweijie94



https://github.com/weiji3x

Tel: +65 9115 4310

Email: weiji3x@gmail.com

Address: Ang Mo Kio Ave 5

Singapore 560181

# **PROFILE**

Data analyst with strong analytical and problem-solving skills that excels at identifying business requirements, identifying connections and trend from data sets to generate actionable insights to drive informed decision-making. Equipped with data visualization skills to convey these insights to relevant stakeholders to improve company decision-making. Experienced in project and people management with ability to manage projects and collaborate effectively with diverse teams.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# System Analyst, UOB (United Overseas Bank) September 2022 - November 2023

- Coordinated activities with engineering, infrastructure, security and product team for deployment of risk management web application.
- Worked with the data source team to ensure correct data is being cleaned, transformed, delivered and ingested into the application.
- Developed shell scripts for application operations which are scheduled and run through a scheduler (Control-M).
- Facilitated and participated in application testing in SIT, UAT with testing team and end users.
- Set up of user management configuration (function and accessibility of different types of users) for web application.

# **Development Engineer, A\*STAR - ARTC** (Advanced Remanufacturing & Technology Centre) August 2019 - June 2022

- Engaged in research with industry partners to address industry issues/gaps/needs for digital factory simulation and digital twin.
- Led project scoping with internal and external stakeholders to establish communication plans, built project schedules and established clear project deliverables and milestones.
- Executed and delivered technical projects/workstreams regarding digital factory simulation and digital twin.
- Designed and simulated digital factory in 3D simulation model.
- Analysed and optimised simulated production line.
- Created digital twin of live physical production line.

# **SKILLS**

## **Data Analytics:**

- **Data Cleaning**
- Data Manipulation
- **Predictive Modeling**
- Machine Learning Modeling

#### **Data Visualization:**

Tableau

#### Database:

- Oracle
- **PostgreSQL**

#### 3D Simulation & Modeling:

- Siemens Tecnomatix
- Siemens NX
- Solidworks
- Emulate3D

#### **Programming:**

- Python
- Shell-scripting (Linux)

Microsoft (Words, Excel, PowerPoint)

**Project Management** 

#### **LANGUAGUES**

- English
- Chinese

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certificate in Data Analytics, Career Foundry.

Attained in September 2024

**User Experience Design Bootcamp (IBF-STS** P210802XCG), Vertical Institute.

Attained in August 2022

**Develop a Risk Management** Implementation Plan (MF-COM-402E-1), ASRETEC PTE. LTD.

Attained in October 2020

Programme Management (ICT-PMT-3002-1.1), EPM Training Services PTE. LTD.

Attained in March 2020

# **PROJECTS**

# **Influenza Death Analysis of United States**

- Cleaned and analyze historical data from CDC dataset to identify trends in the Influenza outbreak in United States.
- Built Tableau dashboards to present trends found and recommended a staffing plan for the upcoming Influenza season.
- Applications used for project:
  - ✓ Excel
  - ✓ Tableau

# **Video & Customers Analysis of Video Rental Company**

- Conducted an SQL data analysis on the company database to provide the management with insights on their current customer base.
- Performed data cleaning and data extraction from database using CTE and subqueries to group and gather required data for analysis.
- Generated visualization to present to stakeholders regarding their customer base and recommendations on how to improve their business strategies.
- Applications used for project:
  - ✓ Excel
  - ✓ Tableau
  - ✓ PostgreSQL

# **Consumer Behavior Analysis of Online Grocery Store**

- Carried out an analysis on Instacart customer's dataset to extract insights on customers behaviors and sales pattern.
- Produced visualization to present to stakeholders to answer their question regarding customer behaviors and customer segmentations.
- Gave recommendations on how to improve their marketing and segmentation strategies.
- Application used for project:
  - ✓ Excel
  - ✓ Python

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree in Mechanical Engineering Nanyang Technological University, Singapore (Aug 2016 – Jun 2019)

GPA: 4.69/5.00

Graduated with First Class Honours

Diploma in Aerospace Technology with Minor in Business Management Ngee Ann Polytechnic, Singapore (Apr 2011 – May 2014)

GPA: 3.94/4.00

 Graduated with Merit (Top 10% of Cohort)